Guide to the International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union Fishermen and Allied Workers Division, Local 3 Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union Fishermen and Allied Workers Division Local 3 records
1935-1981
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
3466
3466-001
International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union.$bFishermen and Allied Workers Division.$bLocal 3 (Seattle, Wash.)
21.58 cubic feet (20 boxes)
Administrative papers of a labor union representing several dozen local units.
Union composed of several dozen local units. Two predecessors of the Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's union were the United Fishermen's Union of the Pacific, Puget Sound District, and International Fishermen and Allied Workers of America, Pacific District, Local 3 (IFAWA). The IFAWA includes about 15 small local unions as well as larger member unions such as the Alaska Fishermen's Unions .The IFAWA merged with ILWU in 1950. It was active with external organizations such as the Maritime Federation of the Pacific.
A detailed history of the UFU and IFAWA was created by Leo Baunach for the online Waterfront Workers History Project. A link, active as of 8/1/2016, can be found here This essay covers this history of the UFU and IFAWA. Less is written about these unions post-1950, after the merge with the International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union.
As part of an update to the Legacy Inventory, records were arranged into 13 Records Subgroups.
RECORDS SUBGROUP 1: UNITED FISHERMEN'S UNION OF THE PACIFIC, UNITED. PUGET SOUND DISTRICT (UFU) (1935-1948) The UFU is a predecessor of the ILWU Local #3.
RECORDS SUBGROUP 2: SALMON PURSE SEINERS UNION OF THE PACIFIC (1935-1943). Merged with UFU Puget Sound District in 1937.
RECORDS SUBGROUP 3: HERRING FISHERMEN'S UNION OF THE PACIFIC (1936-1948) Merged with UFU Puget Sound District in 1937
RECORDS SUBGROUP 4: INTERNATIONAL FISHERMEN AND ALLIED WORKERS OF AMERICA. PACIFIC DISTRICT. LOCAL #3 (1936-1958)
RECORDS SUBGROUP 5: NORTHWEST IFAWA COUNCIL (1936, 1948-1950)
RECORDS SUBGROUP 6: FEDERATED FISHERMEN'S COUNCIL OF THE PACIFIC COAST (1937-1944)
RECORDS SUBGROUP 7: INTERNATIONAL LONGSHOREMEN'S AND WAREHOUSEMEN'S UNION. INTERNATIONAL. FISHERMEN AND ALLIED WORKERS DIVISION. LOCAL #3 (1938-1982)
RECORDS SUBGROUP 8: WASHINGTON STATE INDUSTRIAL UNION COUNCIL (1940-1949)
RECORDS SUBGROUP 9: MARITIME FEDERATION OF THE PACIFIC (1937-1971)
RECORDS SUBGROUP 10: SEATTLE CIO COUNCIL (1944-1949)
RECORDS SUBGROUP 11: SALMON CONSERVATION LEAGUE (1944)
RECORDS SUBGROUP 12: GOVERNOR'S PINK SALMON ADVISORY COMMITTEE (1954-1956)
RECORDS SUBGROUP 13: WASHINGTON COMMONWEATLH FEDERATION MINUTES (1944)
Correspondence, minutes, negotiations, agreements, and related papers of this large union representing several dozen local units. Includes records of three main predecessor organizations: United Fishermen's Union of the Pacific Puget Sound District; International Fishermen and Allied Workers of America. Pacific District. Local 3.; and the main body of the accession, the Longshoremen's Union records.
Commonly recurring series within this collection are Minutes (for Locals, Executive Boards, Conferences and Conventions), Working and Price Agreements, Financial Records, and Organizational Features. There was a great deal of redundant information within Working Agreements with the only discernable difference between several copies of these multi-page forms being whose signature can be found at the end of each. Working Agreements for fishermen were between a Union and and Owner/Captain of a specific ship on behalf of a Union member. Fish Price Agreements set a minimum price per pound for buyers of fish. These agreements also contain additional documentation of the agreements including related correspondence, meeting minutes, and other material. Financial records contain the ledgers and reports of the unions as well as tax and welfare records for individual members. Forms and lists with Social Security Numbers were copied, the numbers were redacted, and the old forms were destroyed.
Potential items of interest include folder 3/33. Cannery and Fishpacking Companies. It contains lists of employees at Puget Sound Fishpacking and Cannery plants. Agreements with Fishpackers and Canneries are unusual among UFU working agreements in this collection, as are extent lists of employees. More unusual is that they contain lists of employees at several Puget Sound Canneries, many of whom are women. Folder 5/16 Correspondence Dealing With Application for Charter with the International Seamen Union (1935-1936) details efforts by the Salmon Purse Seinser's Union of the Pacific to become affiliated with the International Seamen's Union of America. The Secretary-Treasurer of the Purse Seiner's Union wrote out to many westcoast fishermen's union asking why their application was being withheld. This shows many of the unions that the Salmon Purse Seiners corresponded with. The IFAWA Local #3, MEMBERSHIP LISTS in folders 6/9-16 folders includes member names, addresses, book numbers, and ages of members. Additionally, folders 6/13, 15 contain lists of fishing vessels and the members who worked aboard them. SUBJECT SERIES-NORTHWEST SHOREWORKERS COUNCIL (1946-1950 in folders 7/3-6includes material on Taft-Hartley legislation such as Union declarations and correspondence with congressmen. ASSORTED INTEROFFICE FILES (1946-1950) in folders 7/10,32 include a report with a maps of the "Geographical Distribution of Locals on the Pacific Coast and Territory of Alaska of the International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Unions." This could be useful contextual information. It also includes petitions for President Truman to ban and Atomic and Hydrogen bombs. Folder 8/21: Assorted (1950) contains a working agreement written in Spanish. The series on IFAW PRICE NEGOTIATIONS (1948-1950) Documents the price negotiations surrounding the fall 1949 IFAWA strike. Folder 10/15 concerns the strike itself, which was represented a new tactic of directly confronting and picketing packers. A series of REPORTS (1949-1978)in folders 16/22-24, 17/15 illustrates international labor relations and the state of west commercial fishing.
Open to all users, but access to portions of the papers restricted. Contact repository for details.
The record series TRAILS AND CLAIMS FILES in Box 19 has been restricted to protect the privacy of grievants.
Donated by Robert Quaring, 1/20/1983.
International Woodworkers of America, Accession 4000-001, 4000-002.
Jurich, Joseph F.; International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union.$bFishermen and Allied Workers Division.$bLocal 3 (Seattle, Wash.)$vArchives; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington)
Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor History; Labor Unions; Fishing and Canning; Washington (State); Seattle
- UNITED FISHERMEN'S UNION OF THE PACIFIC, UNITED. PUGET SOUND DISTRICT., 1935-1949; RECORDS SUBGROUP 1 (Box-folder 1/1-6/5, 19/1-19/4)
  - ORGANIZATIONAL FEATURES - Constitutions, By-Laws, and Reports, circa 1935-1942; SERIES I (Box-folder 1/2)
  - MEMBERSHIP RECORDS, 1940, 1944; SERIES II (Box-folder 1/3)
  - INVESTIGATIONS AND TRIALS, 1938-1941; SERIES III (Box-folder 1/4-1/5)
    - Local Meeting Minutes and Constitution, 1946 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - CORRESPONDENCE, 1943-1944; SERIES IV (Box-folder 1/6, 2/17, 2/32)
    - District Office General Letters to Locals, 1944 (Box-folder 1/6)
    - CORRESPONDENCE-International Fishermen and Allied Workers of America. Bellingham Local #5., April 3 1944 (Box-folder 2/17)
    - Correspondence, 1943 (Box-folder 2/32)
  - MINUTES, 1935-1945; SERIES V (Box-folder 1/7-1/14, 2/1-2/16, 2/18-2/31, 2/33-2/45, 3/1-3/6, 5/9, 6/1, 20/1-20/3)
    - International Seamen's Union. Fishermen's Unions Conference, 1936 (Box-folder 1/7)
    - includes Meeting with Boat Owners' Association, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Minutes, 1940, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 1/9)
    - United Fishermen's Union of the Pacific. Reports and Executive Committee, 1937-1941 (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Minutes, 1937-1940 (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Salmon Purse Seiners Union of the Pacific, December 1937-1938 (Box-folder 1/12)
    - includes Puget Sound Operators and United Fishermen's Union Constitution, May-July 1938 (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Assorted California, Oregon, and Alaska Minutes and Resolutions, circa 1935-1941 (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Minutes, 1939-1941 (Box-folder 20/1)
    - Minutes, January-July 1942 (Box-folder 20/2)
    - Minutes, August 1942-March 1944 (Box-folder 20/3)
    - Original Local Minutes (Part 1 of 2), 1942 (Box-folder 1/15)
    - Original Local Minutes (Part 2 of 2), 1942 (Box-folder 1/16)
    - includes Salmon Purse Seiners of the Pacific, 1936 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Salmon Purse Seiners. Anacortes Local., 1935-1937 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - includes Kodiak Minutes, Joint Meeting with Boat Owners' Representatives, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Seattle Local #4, January-May 1941 (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Seattle Local #4, 1940 (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Seattle Local #4, 1939 (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Seattle Local #4, 1938 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Seattle Local #4, 1945 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Gig Harbor Local #8 and Tacoma Local #1, 1945 (Box-folder 2/9)
    - Anacortes Local #2, 1945 (Box-folder 2/10)
    - Everett Local #3, 1945 (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Minutes, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 2/12)
    - Tacoma Emergency Committee, February 1944 (Box-folder 2/13)
    - Emergency Committee Local #2 Anacortes, 1944 (Box-folder 2/14)
    - Everett Local #3, February 9 1944 (Box-folder 2/15)
    - Seattle Local #4, 1944 (Box-folder 2/16)
    - Gig Harbor Local #8, 1944 (Box-folder 2/18)
    - Labor Coordinating Committee. Alaska Salmon Industry., January 20 1944 (Box-folder 2/19)
    - Everett Local #3, 1943 (Box-folder 2/20)
    - Seattle Local #4, 1943 (Box-folder 2/21)
    - Anacortes Local #2, 1943 (Box-folder 2/22)
    - Tendermen Local #9, 1943 (Box-folder 2/23)
    - Gig Harbor Local #8, 1943 (Box-folder 2/24)
    - Bellingham Local #5, 1943 (Box-folder 2/25)
    - Tacoma Local #1, 1943 (Box-folder 2/26)
    - Everett Local #3, January-May 1941 (Box-folder 2/27)
    - Everett Local #3, 1940 (Box-folder 2/28)
    - Everett Local #3, 1939 (Box-folder 2/29)
    - Everett Local #3, 1938 (Box-folder 2/30)
    - Bellingham Local #5, 1935-1937 (Box-folder 2/31)
    - Tacoma Local #1, 1941 (Box-folder 2/33)
    - Tacoma Local #1, 1940 (Box-folder 2/34)
    - Tacoma Local #1, 1939 (Box-folder 2/35)
    - Tacoma Local #1, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 2/36)
    - Gig Harbor Local #8, 1940-1941 (Box-folder 2/37)
    - Gig Harbor Local #8, 1939 (Box-folder 2/38)
    - Gig Harbor Local #8, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 2/39)
    - Otter Trawlers Local #11, 1938-January 1941 (Box-folder 2/40)
    - Pulsbo Local #7, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 2/41)
    - California District Executive Councils - (Minutes and Reports), 1938-1939 (Box-folder 2/42)
    - California District Executive Councils - (Minutes and Reports), 1940-1942 (Box-folder 2/43)
    - California District Local, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 2/44)
    - Bellingham Local #5, 1938-1942 (Box-folder 2/45)
    - Minutes, 1941-1943 (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Minutes, 1940 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Minutes, 1939 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Minutes, 1938 (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Minutes, 1939-1942 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Minutes, 1938-1942 (Box-folder 3/6)
    - United Fishermen's Union of the Pacific - Executive Board, April 16 1940 (Box-folder 5/9)
    - United Fishermen's Union of the Pacific - Executive Board, 1944 (Box-folder 6/1)
  - WORKING AGREEMENTS, 1935-1946; SERIES VI (Box-folder 3/7-3/33, 3/37, 4/1, 4/5, 4/12)
    - Herring Agreement, 1944 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Tendermen's Agreement, 1944 (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Southwestern Seine Fish Price Agreement, 1941 (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Sardine Working Agreement, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Seine Pursers Working Agreement, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Tendermen's Agreements, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 3/12)
    - Herring Agreement, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 3/13)
    - Shark Net Fishing Agreement, 1943 (Box-folder 3/14)
    - Working Agreement for Salmon Purse Seine Boats and Rider (1 of 2), 1942 (Box-folder 3/15)
    - Working Agreement for Salmon Purse Seine Boats and Rider (2 of 2), 1942 (Box-folder 3/16)
    - Sardine Working Agreement, 1942 (Box-folder 3/17)
    - Tendermen, 1942 (Box-folder 3/18)
    - Salmon Purse Seine, 1941 (Box-folder 3/19)
    - Sardine Working Agreement, 1941 (Box-folder 3/20)
    - Sardine Working Agreement, 1941 (Box-folder 3/21)
    - Herring Agreement (part 1 of 2), 1940 (Box-folder 3/22)
    - Herring Agreement (part 2 of 2), 1940 (Box-folder 2/23)
    - Herring Agreement, 1940 (Box-folder 3/24)
    - Far North Shipping and Packing Company, 1940 (Box-folder 3/25)
    - Salmon Purse Seiners - Working Agreement, 1940 (Box-folder 3/26)
    - Tendermen's Agreement, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 3/27)
    - Tendermen's Agreement, 1946 (Box-folder 3/28)
    - Herring Agreement, 1946 (Box-folder 3/29)
    - Working Agreements, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 3/30)
    - Tendermen's Agreement, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 3/31)
    - Salmon Purse Seiners Working Agreement, 1944 (Box-folder 3/32)
    - Cannery and Fishpacking Companies, includes employee name lists, 1938-1939, 1942 (Box-folder 3/33)
    - Joint Agreement with Alaska Canned Salmon Industry, 1938-1948 (Box-folder 3/37)
    - Herring Agreement, 1941 (Box-folder 4/12)
    - Assorted, includes price agreements, 1935-1939 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - 1942 - Sardine Price Agreement (Box-folder 4/5)
  - PRICE NEGOTIATIONS, 1938-1949; SERIES VII (Box-folder 3/34-3/36, 4/23)
    - Southwest Alaska Negotiations, 1938-1940, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 3/34)
    - Herring Negotiations, 1942 (Box-folder 3/35)
    - Southwest Alaska Price Negotiations, 1949 (Box-folder 3/36)
    - Southeast Alaska Salmon Negotiations, 1946 (Box-folder 4/23)
  - PRICE AGREEMENTS, 1940-1945; SERIES VIII (Box-folder 4/2-4/4, 4/6-4/11, 4/13-4/22, 4/24)
    - Puget Sound Cannery Agreement, 1944 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Fresh Fish Agreement, 1944 (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Summer Season 1943 (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Fresh Fish Puget Sound, 1941 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Puget Sound Salmon Cannery Agreement, 1942 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Otter Trawlers Agreement, 1942 (Box-folder 4/8)
    - Fresh Fish Agreement, 1942 (Box-folder 4/9)
    - Sardine Price - Pilchard Packing/Reduction Plants, 1940 (Box-folder 4/10)
    - Sardine Price - Pilchard Packing/Reduction Plants, 1941 (Box-folder 4/11)
    - Otter Trawlers Agreement, 1941 (Box-folder 4/13)
    - Puget Sound Cannery Agreement, 1945 (Box-folder 4/14)
    - Puget Sound Salmon Agreement, 1941 (Box-folder 4/15)
    - Southwest Alaska Salmon Agreement, 1946 (Box-folder 4/16)
    - Southwest Alaska Salmon Agreement, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 4/17)
    - Southeastern Purse Seine Salmon Agreement, 1940 (Box-folder 4/18)
    - Southwestern Alaska Purse Seine Salmon Agreement, 1940 (Box-folder 4/19)
    - Southwestern Alaska Purse Seine Salmon Agreement, 1940 (Box-folder 4/20)
    - Puget Sound Salmon Agreement, 1940 (Box-folder 4/21)
    - Otter Trawlers Agreement, 1940 (Box-folder 4/22)
    - Miscellaneous Agreements 1950-1951 (Box-folder 4/24)
  - FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1936-1946; SERIES IX (Box-folder 4/25-4/38)
    - Washington Unemployment Compensation, 1945 (Box-folder 4/25)
    - Statements of Cash Receipts and Disbursements. Resolutions Selecting Depository of Funds (Banks), 1945 (Box-folder 4/26)
    - Statements of Cash Receipts and Disbursements. Resolutions Selecting Depository of Funds (Banks), 1943-1944 (Box-folder 4/27)
    - U.S. Social Security - 1944 (1 of 2) (Box-folder 4/28)
    - U.S. Social Security - 1944 (2 of 2) (Box-folder 4/29)
    - U.S. Social Security - 1946. Statements of Cash Receipts and Disbursements. (Box-folder 4/30)
    - U.S. Withholding Tax, 1944 (Box-folder 4/31)
    - Washington Unemployment Compensation, 1939-1943 (Box-folder 4/32)
    - United Fishermen's Union Local #9 Tendermen, 1940-1943 (Box-folder 4/33)
    - U.S. Social Security, 1937-1939 (Box-folder 4/34)
    - U.S. Social Security, 1940-1942 (Box-folder 4/35)
    - U.S. Withholding Tax and Social Security - 1943 (Box-folder 4/36)
    - Reports (1 of 2), 1936-1943 (Box-folder 4/37)
    - Reports (2 of 2), 1936-1943 (Box-folder 4/38)
  - UFU TRIALS AND CLAIMS, 1940-1947; SERIES X (Box-folder 19/1-19/4)
    Restricted
    - Claims, 1943 (Box-folder 19/1)
    - Claims Settled, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 19/2)
    - Claims Settled, 1947 (Box-folder 19/3)
    - Hearings, 1940-1942 (Box-folder 19/4)
  - CONFERENCES AND CONVENTIONS, December 5 1938-December 21 1945; SERIES XI (Box-folder 4/39-4/44, 5/1-5/4)
    - UFU Conference File, 42724-21 1945 (Box-folder 4/39)
    - First Annual Convention, 42709-9 1938 (Box-folder 4/40)
    - Constitutional Convention, 42706-4 1940 (Box-folder 4/41)
    - Pacific Coast Fishermen's Union 6th Annual Convention, 42374-11 1939 (Box-folder 4/42)
    - Second Annual Convention, 42715-14 1939 (Box-folder 4/43)
    - Pacific Coast Fishermen's Union 5th Annual Convention, 42374-15 1938 (Box-folder 4/44)
    - Assorted Proceedings from Salmon Purse Seiners, Northwest Conferences, Constitutional Convention, and Annual Convention, 1935-1940 (Box-folder 5/1)
    - EXECUTIVE COUNCIL - Minutes, 1943 (Box-folder 5/2)
    - EXECUTIVE COUNCIL - Conference and Meeting Minutes, 1942, 1945 (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Second All-Alaska Labor Convention, January 12-15 1940 (Box-folder 5/4)
  - MERGER CONVENTION OF DEEP SEA AND PURSE SEINE FISHERMEN'S UNION OF CALIFORNIA, SALMON PURSE SEINERS UNION OF THE PACIFIC, HERRING FISHERMEN'S UNION OF THE PACIFIC, 1937; SERIES XII (Box-folder 6/4)
  - CONSTITUTION AND BY-LAWS OF TRAWL FISHERMEN'S UNION OF THE PACIFIC, 1937; SERIES XIII (Box-folder 6/6)
  - FISHERIES CODE, circa. 1935; SERIES XIV (Box-folder 6/7)
  - DEEP SEA AND PURSE SEINE FISHERMEN'S UNION OF CALIFORNIA: THIRD ANNUAL DANCE AND PROGRAM, 1937; SERIES XV (Box-folder 6/8)
- SALMON PURSE SEINERS UNION OF THE PACIFIC, 1935-1943; RECORDS SUBGROUP 2 (Box-folder 5/5-5/8, 5/10-5/17, 6/3)
  - Membership Roll and Individual Record of Dues, Assessments, etc., circa 1936-circa 1939 (Box-folder 5/5)
  - Membership Roll and Individual Record of Dues, Assessments, etc., circa 1936-circa 1943 (Box-folder 5/6)
  - Local Meeting Minutes 1935-1937 (Box-folder 5/7)
  - Local Meeting Minutes 1937 (Box-folder 5/8)
  - Local Records of Members, circa 1938 (Box-folder 5/10)
  - Minutes, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 5/11)
  - Minutes, 1936 (Box-folder 5/12)
  - Correspondence and Reports, esp. re: Conrad Espe, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 5/13)
  - Salmon Purse Seiners Correspondence and Reports, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 5/14)
  - Salmon Purse Seiners 1937 Price-Weight Reports. Second Convention. (Box-folder 5/15)
  - Correspondence Dealing With Application for Charter with the International Seamen's Union, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 5/16)
  - Headquarters File - Contains Assorted Minutes, Reports, and Correspondence, 1937 (Box-folder 5/17)
  - Second Annual Convention, March 14-15 1940 (Box-folder 6/3)
- HERRING FISHERMEN'S UNION OF THE PACIFIC, 1936-May 14 1938; RECORDS SUBGROUP 3 (Box-folder 5/18, 6/2, 6/5, 6/17-6/18)
  - Herring Fishermen Membership Records, 1936 (Box-folder 5/18)
  - Minutes, May 6 1937-May 14 1938 (Box-folder 6/2)
  - International Seamen's Union of America Secretary-Treasurer Correspondence, 1937 (Box-folder 6/5)
  - Minutes, 1936-February 4 1937 (Box-folder 6/17)
  - Minutes of the Herring Fishermen's Union of the Pacific, February 12 1937-April 29 1937 (Box-folder 6/18)
- INTERNATIONAL FISHERMEN AND ALLIED WORKERS OF AMERICA. PACIFIC DISTRICT. LOCAL #3, 1936-1958; RECORDS SUBGROUP 4 (Box-folder 6/9-12/23)
  - MEMBERSHIP LISTS, 1943-1950; SERIES I (Box-folder 6/9-6/16)
    - Membership Lists, 1943-1944, 1946 (Box-folder 6/9)
    - Commercial Fishing Licenses 1947 (Box-folder 6/10)
    - Membership Lists, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 6/11)
    - Membership Lists, 1948 (Box-folder 6/12)
    - "Stencils to be cut" list. List of Purse Seine Fishing Boats Cleared for 1949 Herring Operation. Inactive Membership. (Box-folder 6/13)
    - International Fishermen and Allied Workers of America Pacific District Local #3 Inactive Membership February 10, 1949 (Box-folder 6/14)
    - Purse Seine Vessels Cleared: Summer Season 1949 (Box-folder 6/15)
    - Vessels Cleared/Not Cleared, 1950 (Box-folder 6/16)
  - CORRESPONDENCE, 1943-1947, 1958; SERIES II (Box-folder 6/19, 7/24, 12/20)
    - Correspondence, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 6/19)
    - Policy Statement on Alaska Conservation Program, 1947 (Box-folder 7/24)
    - Alaska Fishermen's Union- Letter to Congress Re: Bottom Fish Industry, 1958 (Box-folder 12/20)
  - MINUTES, 1939-1950; SERIES III (Box-folder 6/20-7/2, 7/7-7/9, 7/11-7/22, 7/25-7/33, 7/35, 7/37)
    - Special Meetings, 1947 (Box-folder 6/20)
    - Tacoma Unit, 1947-January 13 1948 (Box-folder 6/21)
    - Anacortes Unit, 1947 (Box-folder 6/22)
    - Everett Unit, 1947-January 9 1948 (Box-folder 6/23)
    - Bellingham Unit, 1947-January 8 1948 (Box-folder 6/24)
    - Gig Harbor Unit, 1947-January 8 1948 (Box-folder 6/25)
    - Crab Conference Minutes, November 15-16 1947 (Box-folder 6/26)
    - Membership Meeting, January 8 1947 (Box-folder 6/27)
    - Crab Fishermen's Unit, 1946 (Box-folder 6/28)
    - United Fishermen's Union of the Pacific, Puget Sound District, 1938-1941 (Box-folder 6/29)
    - Price Committee Meetings, 1946 (Box-folder 6/30)
    - Tacoma Unit #1, 1946 (Box-folder 6/31)
    - Anacortes Unit, 1946 (Box-folder 6/32)
    - Local #3 Everett, 1946 (Box-folder 6/33)
    - Local #4 Seattle, 1946 (Box-folder 6/34)
    - Local #5 Bellingham, 1946 (Box-folder 6/35)
    - Local #8 Gig Harbor, 1946 (Box-folder 6/36)
    - Executive Board Meeting. United Fishermen's Union of the Pacific, Puget Sound District, Northwest Conference, 1939-1942 (Box-folder 6/37)
    - Local #9 Tendermen, May 15 1946 (Box-folder 6/38)
    - Assorted Minutes, 1937-1940, 1942 (Box-folder 6/39)
    - IFAWA Local #34 San Francisco - 1945 (Box-folder 6/40)
    - Assorted Minutes, 1937, 1943, 1946 (Box-folder 6/41)
    - Assorted Bulletins and Minutes of Local #3 and Unites, includes material about the International Longshoremen and Warehousemen's Union and its proposed merge with the IFAW (1 or 2), 1948-1950 (Box-folder 7/1)
    - Assorted Bulletins and Minutes of Local #3 and Unites, includes material about the International Longshoremen and Warehousemen's Union and its proposed merge with the IFAW (2 or 2), 1948-1950 (Box-folder 7/2)
    - Trial Committee Minutes and Correspondence, July-August 1950 (Box-folder 7/7)
    - 1949 Minutes - Unit #4 - Seattle (Box-folder 7/8)
    - IFAWA Minutes Miscellaneous 1948-1949 (Box-folder 7/9)
    - Unit #5 - Bellingham, 1949 (Box-folder 7/11)
    - Gig Harbor, 1949 (Box-folder 7/12)
    - Policy Committee, October 5-10 1949 (Box-folder 7/13)
    - Strike Committee, October 4-19 1949 (Box-folder 7/14)
    - Various Special Meetings, 1949 (Box-folder 7/15)
    - Crab Division, 1949 (Box-folder 7/16)
    - Herring Division, 1949 (Box-folder 7/17)
    - Sardine Division, 1949 (Box-folder 7/18)
    - Unit #3 - Everett, 1949 (Box-folder 7/19)
    - Minutes and Secretary-Treasurer's Reports, 1947-1949 (Box-folder 7/20)
    - Crab Unit Minutes and Correspondence, 1948-January 1949 (Box-folder 7/21)
    - Herring Unit Minutes, 1948 (Box-folder 7/22)
    - Unit 2, Anacortes - Regular Meeting Minutes, 1949 (Box-folder 7/25)
    - 1949 Board and Unit 1, Tacoma Meeting Minutes (Box-folder 7/26)
    - 1948 Sardine Unit (Box-folder 7/27)
    - Unit #4 - Seattle, 1948 (Box-folder 7/28)
    - Unit #2 - Anacortes, 1948 (Box-folder 7/29)
    - Unit #3 - Everett, 1948 (Box-folder 7/30)
    - Unit #5 - Bellingham, 1948 (Box-folder 7/31)